DAVID D. RYU

#2421, 45 Dunfield Avenue, Toronto, Ontario (M4S 2H4) (647) 989-0923 | ryu923can@gmail.com | David-Ryu-LinkedIn

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Creative and experienced software developer and also having experience in a broad range of varied industry segments. Proven programming skills in writing, developing, and testing acumen and leadership qualities based on military service as an officer to support working within multinational organizations with responsibility and interpersonal skills.

Areas of knowledge and experience include:

☐ Front-End Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6	☐ Back-End Development: Java, C#, ASP.NET, SQL
☐ Testing and Quality: JUnit, TFS, Selenium IDE	□ Operating Systems: Microsoft, Unix, Linux
□ Methodologies: Agile	☐ Financial Knowledge: Project Financing, Stock, Fund
$\hfill \square$ Industrial Experience: Bank, Construction, Education, Sales	☐ Leadership: Company Commander in Military Service

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Diploma | Centennial College

School of Engineering Technology and Applied Science(SETAS), Toronto, Ontario (2016~2018)

Studied full-stack software development from front-end and back-end programming and conducted several software development projects as below

- Police Cam Patrol System: Improvement of recording activation in specific situation; vehicle impact, officer-down, and central dispatch.
- Library Web Development: Tracking an available date of rented book
- CarCare (Car Maintenance Application for iOS): Auto car maintenance notification iOS app based on odometer and time.
- Participated Hackathon Event: Academic grade tracking application for empowering students

Web Publisher (Graduate Certificate) | The Joeun Computer Art School South Korea (2013)

Studied front-end web development in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and web-design in Photoshop and

Studied front-end web development in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and web-design in Photoshop and Illustrator.

Bachelor of Business Administration and Management
Bachelor of Sports Informatics and Science

| University of Seoul | University of Seoul

Double Major, South Korea (2002~2006)

EXPERIENCE

Front-End Web Developer

Freelancer - Seoul, South Korea (2013 ~ 2016)

• Improvement web of education company: 23% increased in the number of accumulated visitors per quarter and the average number of new registers per quarter increased from 81 to 102.

- Developed and redesigned web sales advertisement: Focused on holiday event web advertisement and 32% increasing of holiday sales in online shopping mall.
- Participated Volkswagen motor company's web-banner advertisement contest.

Assistant Engineer

IS DongSeo-Korea Lift Rental, South Korea (2013 ~ 2015)

- Improvement of analyzing and diagnosis time for machines with management of computerized diagnosis hardware: Reduced diagnosis time to 1/3 (30 minutes to 8 minutes).
- Managed upgrading software for Electronic Control Unit(ECU) of machine: 1,200 machines.

KOR-US Army Management Information Officer(MIO), Company Commander

UN Military Police(MP), KOR-US Army at Camp Humphreys, South Korea (2006 ~ 2010)

Managed a team of MIO and worked on intelligent software for KOR-US Army and in charged of specialties as below

- Integrated the information software panel to trace maneuver damage simulation of divisions
- Managed connection among military information software, military satellite, and high-altitude reconnaissance plane on KOR-US combined military exercise

Banker, International Financial Department

Korea Development Bank, South Korea (2012)

- Analysis of business management information for CEO
- Developed risk management model for project financing: Analyzing impact of stress test in global financial crisis and developed AMA (Advanced Measurement Approach) for bank management risk

ADDITIONAL SKILLS & SOCIAL ACTIVITIES

Hard-Skills

Design Skills - Adobe Illustration, Photoshop

Financial Skills - CFIA (Certified Fund Investment Advisor)

- CSIA (Certified Securities Investment Advisor)

- Publication (Certified Securities Investment Reference E-Book)

Engineering Skills - Electrical System

Soft-Skills

Teamwork - Expertise in military team operations

- Performed a variety of projects in financial, education, and construction

companies.

Leadership - Captain in military service and President of student council at University

• Generalized Specialist - Financial, Business, Engineering, Sports experience and knowledge

Volunteer & Competition

- Canada International Auto-show Organization Showroom Volunteer (2016)
 - Electrical painting hardware and software demonstration
- Centennial College Hackathon Event (2018)
 - Student Academic Tracking App